

# **Abu Sufiun**

I try to work with passion and honesty. I think polite behavior and team working can make any work easy. I have two years of experience in the field of Database Management System and Full Stack Web Development moreover an expert in Data analysis, Machine learning & Image Processing. Furthermore, publish research papers in journal and conference also like to explore and learn new things.

Address: Akur Takur Para, Tangail 1900, Bangladesh

Nationality: Bangladeshi

Mobile: (+880) 1878000675

Date of birth: 15/04/1998

O' Gender: Male

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### TEACHING APPRENTICE FELLOWSHIP - DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

01/1/2020 – 23/12/2021 | Mentorship & Leadership Development Training Program. Helping teachers on lab environment also maintains the leadership of students.

#### **RESEARCH ASSOCIATE - DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY**

01/01/2019 – 01/04/2021 | Maintains the leadership of DIU Research and Innovation Society. Research is an important aspect of student life and the growth of the nation therefore conduct research.

## **EDUCATION**

## BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING - Daffodil International University

CGPA: 3.80 in the scale of 4 01/09/2017 - 26/09/2021

#### HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE – Major General Mahmudul Hasan Adarsha College

CGPA: 4.92 in the scale of 5 | Field of study science | 07/08/2014 – 18/08/2016

## SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE - Dighulia Shahid Mizanur Rahman High School

CGPA: 5.00 in the scale of 5 | Field of study science | 08/01/2012 - 17/05/2014

#### PUBLICATION

## A Novel Approach of CNN Patterns Extraction for Bangla Handwriting to Bangla Braille Notation

Braille is the only tactile dotted learning method for visually impaired people. That work was published in the International Journal of Engineering Advanced Research, [S.l.], v. 3, n. 3, p. 1-15, dec. 2021. ISSN 2710-7167.

#### Braille Character Recognition and Pronunciation with Appropriate Speech

Analysis of pre-trained models to recognize the braille Script and convert it into speech. That accept at Kuala Lumpur International Conference on Multi-Disciplinary Research 2021 (KLIC2021).

## CERTIFICATIONS

<b>Teaching Apprentice Fellowship</b>
HRDI - Daffodil International University.
Cisco Networking Academy Skill Competition
CISCO Network Academy.
ACM – ICPC Asia Dhaka Regional
Preliminary Round Programing Contest.

## > PROJECTS

## **Dynamic Web Application Development**

Developing Web Applications by using Laravel, PHP, MySQL, Oracle, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap & jQuery.

#### **Static Website Development**

Developed Static Website by using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap & jQuery.

#### **Automatic Number Plate Detection and Authentication**

Object detection is a very sophisticated technology to work on nowadays. So, for this project use combination of two object delectation models YOLO v4 and YOLO v5.

## > SKILLS

Web Design & Development	Programming	Data Sciences
HTML, CSS, Bootstrap JavaScript Laravel Database Management System Oracle, MySQL SEO Cyber Security Management SQL Injection, HTML filter	Object-oriented programming C, PHP, Python Data structure Assembly System analysis and design	Machine Learning  Convolution Neural Network  Artificial intelligence  Digital image processing
<b>Operating Systems</b>	Digital electronics	Networking
Windows, macOS, Android DOS, Ubuntu, Unix, Kali Linux	Electric Circuit, Robotic Arduino	Subnetting, IP, MAC Server Management Computer networking
Microsoft Office	Web3	Software
Word, Excel PowerPoint, Pdf	Cryptocurrency, Blockchain Digital Wallet, Gift Card Number Verification, Paypal & Bank Management	PhpStrom, Code Blocks Photoshop, Illustrator NetBeans, XAMPP Packet Tracer Burp suite, Tinkercad EaseUS Data Recovery

## > REFERENCE

## Dr. Md. Ismail Jabiullah

Professor

Department of Computer Science and Engineering Daffodil International University, Bangladesh

Cell Phone: 01819299960 Email: drismail.cse@diu.edu.bd

#### Dr. S.M. Aminul Haque

Associate Professor and Associate Head

Department of Computer Science and Engineering Daffodil International University, Bangladesh

Cell Phone: 01847140129

Email: aminul.cse@daffodilvarsity.edu.bd

## > DECLARATION

I hereby certify that the above informations are true and correct to the best of my knowledge. I understand that a false statement may disqualify me for benefits.

Abu Sufiwn
Signature